江西省2025年初中学业水平考试英语听。
一、听力理解。
本大题共二十小题，每小题一分，共二十分。
哎，请听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一小题，从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最。
加选项，并在答题卡上将该项涂黑。
听完每段对话后，你都将有十秒钟的时间回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话读两遍。
Hi, Alan. What club are you in?
Oh, I'm in the science club.
2. I help you?
Yes, please. I need a cup.
How much is it?
Sixteen yuan. Can I help you?
Yes, please. I need a cup.
How much is it?
Sixteen yuan. 3.
Which season do you like best, Bruce?
Spring, of course.
I was born in it.
Which season do you like best, Bruce?
Spring, of course.
I was born in it.
4. Jack, do you have any plans for Saturday?
Sure. I'm going to play ping pong with my friends.
Do you want to join us, Mary?
Certainly. Jack, do you have any plans for Saturday?
Sure. I'm going to play ping pong with my friends.
Do you want to join us, Mary?
Certainly. 5. Do you like the concert last night?
I saw my favorite singer and my favorite pianist.
Do you like the concert last night?
一，请听下面四段对话，每段对话后有几个小题，从题中所给的
B, and William, this is my family photo.
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并在答题卡上将该项涂黑。
听每段对话前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题给出五秒钟的作答时间，每段对话读两遍。
请听第一段对话，回答第六、七小题。
What a happy family!
What does your father do, Annie?
Oh, he is a doctor.
How about your mother?
She is a teacher, and she is very busy.
So, do you often do chores at home?
Of course. I often do the dishes after dinner.
William, this is my family photo.
What a happy family!
What does your father do, Annie?
Oh, he is a How about your mother?
She is a teacher, and she is very busy.
So, do you often do chores at home?
Of course. I often do the dishes after dinner.
话，回答第八九小题。
Excuse me, sir.
I think I am lost.
Could you please tell me where the city library is?
Oh, it is a bit far.
How can I get there?
You'd better take the subway.
Where is the subway station?
Look. The subway station is right over there.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome. Excuse me, sir.
I think I am lost.
Could you please tell me where the city library is?
Oh, it is a bit far.
How can I get there?
You'd better take the subway.
Where is the subway station?
Look. The subway station is right over there.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome. Hey, Jenny.
请听第三段对话，回答第十至第十二小题。
What's up? Hi, Peter.
Are you enjoying your vacation in Wugong Mountain?
Yes. I'm having a good time with my parents here.
What's the weather like there?
It's really cool, even in summer.
That sounds good.
Yeah, it is.
So how's your vacation in Gansu?
It's also pretty nice.
The people here are very friendly.
Hey, Jenny. What's up?
Hi, Peter. Are you enjoying your vacation in Wugong Mountain?
Yes. I'm having a good time with my parents here.
What's the weather like there?
It's really cool, even in summer.
That sounds good.
Yeah, it is.
So how's your vacation in Gansu?
It's also pretty nice.
The people here are very friendly.
请听第四段对话，回答第十三至第十五小题。
What are you going to do tonight?
I don't know.
I am kind of bored.
I have nothing to do today.
Would you like to see a movie?
Nizha 2 will be on at 7 o 'clock tonight.
Nizha 2? I've never heard of it.
Is it any good?
Sure. Actually, I watched it last Sunday, but I don't mind watching it a second
time. Oh, really?
I suppose I could go and see it.
Great. Since the movie starts at 7 p.m., should I pick you up around 6.30?
Okay. That would be very nice.
See you then.
What are you going to do tonight?
I don't know.
I am kind of bored.
I have nothing to do today.
you like to see a Nizha 2 will be on at 7 o tonight.
Nizha 2? I've never heard of it.
Is it any good?
Sure. Actually, I watched it last Sunday, but I don't mind watching it a second
time. Oh, really?
I suppose I could go and see it.
Great. Since the movie starts at 7 p.m., should I pick you up around 6.30?
Okay. That would be very nice.
See you then.
请听下面一段独白，根据独白内容完成下列句子。
每个空格不超过三个单词。
将答案填写到答题卡的相应位置。
听独白前，你将有五十秒钟的时间阅读句子内容。
独白读两遍。
Thank you. Hello, everyone.
I'm so excited to tell you about our outdoor class.
We're going to the new park near our school on Saturday morning.
We will meet at our school gate at 8 o When everyone arrives, we are going to the
park on foot.
So don't be late.
We're going to look for different kinds of birds all morning and then we're having
lunch together. After lunch, we'll look for some more.
Some scientists will be there to explain things to us.
So don't forget to take a pen because you have to write everything down.
I'm sure all of you will learn more about birds from this special class.
Hello, everyone. I'm so excited to tell you about our outdoor class.
We're going to the new park near our school on Saturday morning.
We will meet at our school gate at 8 o
When everyone arrives, we are going to the park on foot.
So don't be late.
We're going to look for different kinds of birds all morning and then we're having
lunch together. After lunch, we'll look for some more.
Some scientists will be there to explain things to us.
So don't forget to take a pen because you have to write everything down.
I'm sure all of you will learn more about birds from this special class.
听力部分到此结束。